Michał Wadowski

Senior Java Developer

Contact

Address

Warsaw, Poland

Phone

+48 796 334 459

E-mail

wadosm@gmail.com

Github

github.com/Michal-Wadowski

Linkedin

linkedin.com/in/michal-wadowski

Experience and knowledge

Programming languages / technologies

Java: JUnit/Mockito, Lombok, Hibernate Spring: Boot, Security, JPA, Cloud, Kafka Javasript: ES6, JSX, ReactJS, Redux

Python: DataFrame, Numpy

Databases

PostgreSQL/pgSQL, MongoDB,

Liquibase

Other tools / technologies

Kubernetes, Docker compose, AWS, Azure, Maven, GIT, Jenkins

Good practices

TDD, DDD, Clean Architecture, software

design patterns

IDE IntelliJ IDEA

Operating systems

Linux, Windows

Software Development Model

SCRUM

Languages and technologies in past

Android in Kotlin

C, C++

I'm a software development passionate with over 14 years of experience in various technologies and languages. I have been working in Java oriented projects for 5 years mostly using Spring Boot / Security / JPA in combination with PostgreSQL & MongoDB, Kafka, Kubernetes, Docker Compose on AWS & Azure infrastructure. I have frontend background especially in ReactJS and Redux. I value TDD, Clean Code and other good programming practices.

Professional experience

HSBC Service Delivery (Polska) Sp. z o.o.

via Mindbox S.A.

08.2022 - 12.2024

Senior Java Developer

Developing "Strategic Financial Planning" - internal business application written in Java 8 - 21 with Spring Boot in microservices architecture.

Technologies used: JUnit & Mockito, Java Reactor, Lombok, PostgreSQL & Oracle + Liquibase

Kubernetes with **AWS**, **Jenkins** and **ReactJS** were used in project as well

Orange Polska S.A.

02.2022 - 07.2022

Java Developer with

Developing microservices for streaming platform

using Kafka, MongoDB and Java Reactor

Developing Eclipse Leshan library

Orange Polska S.A.

02.2021 - 07.2022

Java Developer

https://www.eclipse.org/leshan in Java for IoT communication protocol (Lightweight M2M).

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

08.2020 - 07.2022

Developing research application ThingIn The City using **Spring Boot** and **PostgreSQL** technologies.

Orange Polska S.A.

Android Developer

03.2020 - 01.2021

Developing mobile application for technicians

using Live Objects platform

https://liveobjects.orange-business.com with Android Studio in Java and Kotlin languages.

As a development model was used SCRUM

framework.

Awans Sp. z o. o.

06.2014 - 02.2020

Full-stack Developer

Developing https://awanser.pl business platform

using technologies:

Frontend: ReactJS with Redux and Ecmascript 6,

CSS, LESS and SCSS

Backend: **PHP** and CakePHP framework, **PostgreSQL** database system, **Azure**

Courses

Creating μ Services using Spring Cloud and Docker

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Spring Framework II

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Pragmatic refactoring using DDD techniques

https://bottega.com.pl

Clean Code in Java

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Test-Driven Development in practice https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Useful characteristics

- Writing good quality code
- Experienced in working with legacy systems
- IT technologies quick learner
- Teamwork skills
- Independence and responsibility

Languages

Polish

Native

English

B2

Passions & hobbies

- Programming microcontrollers and developing electronic circuits
- Building and training artificial neural networks
- Developing applications and devices for own needs
- Astronomy, quantum physics and science in general

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. 01.2013 - 05.2014	Java Developer Developing integration layer with ePUAP system in Java and PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL
Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. 10.2011 - 12.2012	Software Developer Developing of business application in Delphi and PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL
iDelfi Polska Sp. z o. o. 11.2009 - 12.2010	Full-stack Developer Developing internet application for HACCP management in technologies: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, jQuery, MySQL

Training

March 2022	<u>I (PSD I)</u>
Education	
2009 - 2011	University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn
	Field of study: Computer science
	M. Sc.
	Hart and the state of the state

Duefessional Commo Developer

2005 - 2008

University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn
Field of study: Computer systems
Undergraduate course